Guide to the Gertrude Buckman Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Gertrude Buckman correspondence
1944-1997
YCAL MSS 379
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(1 box)
Letters to Gertrude Buckman from various writers, poets, and editors, including John Berryman, James Laughlin, Adrienne Rich, Kurt Vonnegut, and Robert Penn Warren. Letters date from circa 1944-1997 and include a small amount of letters from unidentified correspondents.
Buckman, Gertrude
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Gertrude Buckman on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 1998, and on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Gertrude Buckman
Gertrude Buckman, writer and first wife of author Delmore Schwartz.
Scope and Contents
The Gertrude Buckman Correspondence contains letters from various writers, poets, and editors, including John Berryman, James Laughlin, Adrienne Rich, Kurt Vonnegut, and Robert Penn Warren, spanning 1944-1997.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Buckman, Gertrude
- Gertrude Buckman Correspondence, circa 1944-1997
  Arrangement
  Letters are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. A folder of letters from various correspondents is filed at the end of the box.
  - Abse, Dannie and Joan Abse, undated (Box 1)
  - Atlas, John, 1974, undated (Box 1)
  - Barrett, William, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Charles, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Berger, Thomas, 1956, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Berryman, Eileen, 1952-1959, undated (Box 1)
  - Berryman, John, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Blackmur, Richard, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Boorjaily, Vance, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Brinnen, John Malcom, 1945-1962 (Box 1)
  - Coxhead, Elizabeth, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Eberhart, Richard, 1974 September 15 (Box 1)
  - Engle, Paul, 1954 May 11 (Box 1)
  - Fergusson, Francis, 1962, undated (Box 1)
  - Fine, Irving, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Haffenden, John, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Hamilton, Ian, 1982 June 18 (Box 1)
  - Horton, Philip, 1956 June 14 (Box 1)
  - Kazin, Alfred, 1979, 1997, undated (Box 1)
  - Kriston, Irving, 1962 Nov 1 (Box 1)
  - Kronenberger, Louis, undated (Box 1)
  - Laughlin, James, 1961-1997 (Box 1)
  - Lowell, Elizabeth Hardwick, 1945-1987 (Box 1)
  - Macdonald, Dwight, 1975 December 22, undated (Box 1)
  - Mayberry, George, 1945-1946 (Box 1)
  - McGuire, William, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Miller, Karl, 1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Mosse, George, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Ostroff, Anthony, 1963-1976 (Box 1)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1962 November4 (Box 1)
  - Phillips, Robert, 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  - Phillips, William, 1945-1997 (Box 1)
  - Podhoretz, Norman, 1962 December 13 (Box 1)
  - Raphaels, Max, 1948 May 2 (Box 1)
  - Read, Bill, 1962-1979 (Box 1)
  - Rich, Adrienne, 1960 May 28 (Box 1)
  - Riggs, Lynn, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Roth, Philip, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Roth, Bess and Herman, 1971 October 24, undated (Box 1)
  - Sarton, May, 1974 Nov 12 (Box 1)
  - Schneider, Micha, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Schorer, Mark, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Sharpe, Tom, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Snodgrass, DeWitt, 1957; undated (Box 1)
  - Steegmuller, Francis, 1962 March 26 (Box 1)
  - Swadoes, Harvey, 1957 September 10 (Box 1)
  - Tate, Allen, 1956 October 30 (Box 1)
  - Trilling, Diana, 1975 December 16 (Box 1)
  - Ustinov, Peter, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Vivante, Arturo, 1975 April 24 (Box 1)
  - Vonnegut, Kurt, 1961-1979 (Box 1)
  - Ward, Aileen, undated (Box 1)
  - Warren, Eleanor Clark, 1953-1993 (Box 1)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1954, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Warren, Rosanna, 1993 Oct 31 (Box 1)
  - Wolff, Helen, 1945, 1980-1994 (Box 1)
  - Young, Marguerite, undated (Box 1)
  - Unidentified correspondents, 1953-1982, undated (Box 1)